Good afternoon. Thanks for joining us
this afternoon. And uh we're excited to
welcome Maxonaturer to Pittsburgh today
after a red eye last night. So Max, I
hope you're feeling all right.
>> But uh we're we're pleased to have
somebody who uh you know played in 32
games in his college career. Uh gave up
three sacks uh in 1150 uh uh passing
attempts.
uh and uh you know just had a a great
week at the Senior Bowl. So uh you know
a lot lot to to get excited about Max
being here and of course he is the first
player that we've drafted from Arizona
State since Marbell Smith. So great role
model for you there Max. So I'm pleased
to introduce Max Oner. Uh welcome Max.
>> Sir, thank you so much.
>> All righty sir.
safety work.
>> Uh, I just want to give a special thank
you to, you know, Mr. Rooney right here
for bringing me in, man, giving me
opportunity, Mr. K and, uh, Mr.
McCarthy, man. Thank you for real. You
know, this means a lot to me. I'm ready
to get to work, man.
>> All right, we'll open up questions.
>> What do you know about Mar?
>> Say it again.
>> What do you know about Marl Smith?
>> I know a little bit, man. He played at
uh ASU, got drafted 2000, second round
pick, you know, played here for about
eight years before going to the Niners.
So, he's a really good player, man.
>> First of all, uh, welcome to the story.
Can you pronounce your last name for us?
>> Yeah, last name is pronounced Ihana
Chore.
>> Y
>> through kind of your emotions of the
night of your family. Just what it all
meant and then how you know last night,
how you got here today. Just take us
through your day.
Honestly, man, yesterday is
unbelievable. Just surreal moment for
just me and the family. Um, family was
there, friends was there, coaches that,
you know, was with me where it all
started. Jo. So, I mean, just, you know,
got to really say thank you again to
them in person, man. So, it was really,
it was really a special moment. I'm
happy I got to share that with them.
>> Max, whenever you first started playing
football at junior college, could you
have ever expected this opportunity or
envisioned this opportunity to be a
firstround pick?
>> Oh, When I first started,
honestly, man, I knew it was it was
going to be hard. But obviously, uh, the
vision was there, but I knew it was
going to be hard. So, I mean, just try
to just, you know, just try to just get
better every day, man. and then just put
your head down and work, not to try to
look to ahead and try to just, you know,
predict stuff. Just work every day. That
was my whole motto, man. So, I mean,
yeah.
>> You told us yesterday about your AAU
basketball coach being the inspiration
for making the switch to the football
field. Um, were there was there a
specific conversation that stands out to
you or was it just kind of a cumulative
thing? And what were some of those
conversations like?
>> Um, honestly, like it was after a summer
basketball game. We was in the car. He
just brought it up and he kind of
already kind of told me a little bit but
he brought it up and we actually had a
real conversation in the car and you
know it was a probably like 30 minute
conversation. He was like man look I
know high school's over basketball stuff
man probably look into football cuz he
played back in his day played at San
Jose State you know played like probably
a year or two in the league. Um he was
just really advising me on that telling
me to really look forward to it. I went
down south with the head coach and
he had vision me being offensive lineman
and ever since then it's just been
history. Max, when you started playing,
what did you immediately like about
football? And then what was the hardest
thing for you to get used to?
>> I definitely say, man, football, man.
Like the best thing I loved was just the
process, man. Just going through it,
man. It's going to be hard time just
embracing that moment, just learning
from it. And definitely on the field,
man, just punishing people like in Jo
like that was just fun, you know, just
getting to bully people, man.
>> Max, you've been taking taking us back
further than that. What was it like
coming here to the US from Nigeria as a
as a 13-year-old? I'm guessing football
was pretty far from your mind at that
point.
>> Yeah, I mean our football we called it
it was called football but it was soccer
back home. Uh
man, it's crazy just coming as a kids
just excited. I mean I watched a lot of
American movies seeing snow, you know,
got to see snow for the first time in
Atlanta. That's where we live for 6
months. I remember me and my little
brother right there went outside trying
to catch it and stuff. It was definitely
fun moment as kids, man. But I mean from
my parents just making that transition,
sacrificing everything they have built
back home to put us in a better position
for education. Like big shout out to
them.
>> Max, when you first started playing
football, was it always offensive line
right away? And and what did you sort of
grow to love about that uh that job?
>> Yeah. N Yeah. Only position I ever
played. Yeah, definitely offensive line.
I really had no other choice. I just
coming in that late, man. Um,
head coach saw me offensive line. He
didn't bring another position up and
that was all I was used to and just
played.
>> We talked to your Jo head coach earlier
this morning. He recalled some of the
early days of you playing football,
maybe some of the growing pains you went
through. What were maybe some of the
most difficult things to get a hold of
in those first days? What do you
remember about those first experiences
in football?
>> Um, honestly, man, going in, I mean, I
just remember I keep saying this like I
was like, what the hell is a A gap? Like
a B gap? It was like you got to know all
these things. I'm like, bro, you can't
just line up and just go block. It was
like, nah, you need to know. So, just
being detailed as offensive lineman.
Just knowing the little things really
matter in this game, man. It's game of
inches, you know, being detailed.
Definitely as offensive lineman, that's
key. So, just that whole piece of it,
man, that was just really it.
>> Playing on the right side. Um,
Mike McCarthy spoke last night about
position flexibility and then the
importance of that. Uh, how do you
embrace possibly playing another
position outside of Brighton Tech? Yeah,
I'm open to it. Been training this whole
off seasonason for it. I mean, I play
left tackle, Jo, play right tackle at
ASU, whatever the coaches put me at.
That's where I played. So, I mean, just
open to that. Just, you know, ready to
just get to work.
>> Along those lines, too, how much do you
know about the current guys that are in
that room on the offensive line here?
You're Pittsburgh now. How do you think
you did with with this current group?
>> Yeah. No, I watched I watched a lot I
watched a lot of offensive linemen. Uh,
Brick when he got drafted, Georgia, I
watched him. Um Troy Fatan got to play
him. Um he actually texted me last night
too, you know, welcoming me. Um got to
watch him, you know, played against him
when they won the championship that
year. Uh it was just really cool seeing
him reaching out to me and just
welcoming me. But uh Andrew's Pete, he
played
quiet time. Uh played with his younger
brother at ASU, too. So yeah.
>> M What's your first time in Is this your
first time in this?
>> Yeah, it's my first time. And you
haven't done a lot since this morning,
but what are your first thoughts about
team?
>> It's beautiful. I just remember that
tunnel coming out that tunnel and just
bam, just hit me. I was like, "Okay."
Yeah. Yeah. Liked it.
>> I saw your offensive line coach, Coach
Saga, was talking to us earlier today
and he said that he found you sort of by
accident, junior college cuz he was
going to look at another tackle.
>> Yeah.
>> Do you feel like that was sort of fate
for you to wind up where you did at
Arizona State following him out there?
And do you have the same feeling about
how you wound up here?
>> Nah, I mean honestly, man, everything
happens for a reason, man. It's really
just all God's plan. So, I mean, that's
how, you know, he met me and, you know,
I can't be mad at that. You know, just
the opportunity he see he also got to
recruit the other tackle that was there,
too. He's a hell of a good player. But,
you know, just all guys playing, it all
just worked out in his favor. You know,
without him, none of this is possible.
So, yeah.
>> Do you remember what you did maybe to
impress him, to catch his eye that day?
Honestly, I didn't even We never really
know when coaches really come in
practice. Just like kind of just show up
and watch just practice hard like I
always do. So, I'm you know, he like
that. So, yeah.
>> Nice. When we had talked with your Jo
coach earlier today, he also mentioned a
moment when you came up to him and said,
"I don't know if football is for me. I
don't know if I want to do this
anymore." Looking back at that
personnel, what would be your message?
>> Yeah, I mean, honestly, that first year
was rough. uh you know switching a new
sport uh wasn't playing had to gain
weight and honestly if you if you guys
are used to Nigerian parents like they
love doctors nurses so my mom was kind
of on my ass she was like man you're not
even playing you're wasting your time
like you should go to a fouryear so I
mean just trying to own that respect to
I went in and just really sat down and
like man like my parents you know they
really they wanted me to go to a
fouryear you know that's the whole point
of us coming out here they're really big
on education so I mean the first year
was really rough man but I mean that
just showed you know, I just stay
through it and just, you know, just kept
fighting every day and just trying to
just get better. So, yeah.
>> M, as of right now, what do you enjoy
the most? Pass protect or run block?
>> I love both. You know, I take pride in
both those uh they're very big aspects,
but obviously running the ball really
helps a lot. You know, make everybody
else job easier when you can run the
ball efficiently. But I definitely say
really both. They're pretty high, you
know, protecting the quarterback, just
taking pride in my job. I mean, that's
what I'm here for to pass, protect, and
run block. When you saw Bailey get
drafted so high, did you say, "I beat
that guy."
>> Say it again.
>> You Bailey, the the two pick from Texas
Tech
>> last night he was picked seven.
>> Yeah.
>> Did you say to yourself, "I blocked that
guy. I beat that guy."
>> Uh, I mean, yeah, we I mean, we did beat
him. Um, I mean, they were they went we
was the only loss they had until the
playoffs. So, I mean, he was a great
matchup, man. I also trained with him
this off seasonason. He's a great guy.
Uh just, you know, just both guys just
being competitive, you know, just going
out there and just playing hard. I was I
was excited for him, though. Yeah.
>> Then you think to yourself, hey, I could
do this. I should go out, too.
>> No, I know I could do this for sure
without I know I know for sure I could
do this.
>> What an A gap was when you first, you
know, played this sport. Where do you
feel you're at? Do you feel like you're
still learning in terms of what you need
to do or or where you at in that kind of
especially at the NFL level?
>> No, I'm straight. I'm straight. That was
just, you know, just the little details
in football. Everything else, you know,
it's pretty just, you know, playwise and
stuff. Just really just doing your job.
And yeah, that's just the small details
at the time that I didn't understand. I
thought you just line up and just play,
but n more stuff to it for sure.
>> You're telling that story about
questioning if football was right for
you at one point. Was that the toughest
moment in this journey or just something
else stand out in that regard?
>> Um, that was just I mean, I wouldn't say
it was just tough. It was just like kind
of like everybody around me, even my
basketball coaches from high school and
parents, like they was just like, "Why
did you leave basketball?" You know what
I mean? So, it was kind of tough. I was
really young. I was 17 at the time, just
trying to just figure football out by
myself. So, um, it was definitely a
grown moment for me. Um, definitely
needed. Yeah.
>> Talking about having some doubts at some
point. And then you were saying, you
know, even before that match up with
Texas Tech, you knew you could do this.
Was there a moment in there when that
clicked for you that that you were going
to be able to do this as a career?
>> Uh yeah, I'll definitely say um first
year at ASU, man, just playing that
first year when I got there from Jo. Um
I grew so much in that first year after
that first year and ever since then it's
just been just, you know, just the
confidence level as highest. So yeah,
>> Max, you've you're relatively new to the
game. What how have you developed a love
uh for the game? you know, when when you
hear, you know, Omar and Mike and these
guys talk about finding Steelers,
finding Steelers players, how do you how
do you develop your love for the game?
>> I definitely say, man, like throughout
the whole process, man, that's what I
fell in love with, you know, started
with the process for sure. Just, you
know, waking up every day going and
just, you know, especially in this
position, man, you know, it's one of the
most selfish position out there. So, you
know, just taking pride in my job, man,
and just, you know, going to war with
the brothers next to me. That's what the
whole fun is about. Going out there and
just, you know, all five guys being on
the same page, dominating like that's
fun and winning. I got to win a
championship um Big 12 my one of the
best moments of my life other than last
night. But um yeah,
>> as a as a late comer to football, um do
you feel like teams in the pre-draft
process were kind of trying to see does
this guy really love it? Is is he just
playing because he's big? We all saw the
clip of Braval kind of roughing you up
at the the pro day and getting in your
grill. Was that something that teams
were trying to ask you about in this
process?
>> I wouldn't say no. I mean, man, I
wouldn't say no. I wasn't really
questioned about that. Like just the way
I just go about things, man. If you have
question about my love for the game,
then Just got to just watch harder
like just how I do and just what I
go about, what I'm about as a man. Um,
but I definitely mean the clip was a
clip. He was just, you know, just trying
to just coach me up, hand placement,
stuff like that, and just seeing like my
recovery. Um, yeah.
>> Two more question. Did you do you
remember what you weighed when you
started when you were in high school?
And did you actually grow heightwise too
since you since you started playing
football?
>> Honestly, I probably grew by like an
inch maybe. I'm not too sure on that,
but I hope I did. But weight wise, I was
about like 250 going into Jo. So, yeah.
>> All right, last one. Do you feel like
the moment you're here in Pittsburgh,
you got dropped, do you feel like it's
set in yet? And if so, when did when did
it hit you?
>> Say it again one more time.
>> Did it do you feel like it has set in
yet that you were dropped, you're here
in Pittsburgh, you're now a Pittsburgh
Steeler? Has it set in?
>> Man, I mean, it still feel like it's
crazy. It's crazy still, man. I don't
know if it's it's ever going to die, but
it's really exciting, man. Just being
blessed. All you can ask for in this
life is opportunity, man. You know, God,
you pray for stuff and You just
got to do the work and everything else
falling apart. So, like I said, man,
these guys, big shout out to them.
Forever in depth and ready to get
to work.